Christopher Nguyen

104 Wardlaw Place, Woodbridge, Ontario, L4H0Z9 ZenonZeni@hotmail.com

LinkedIn Profile & GITHUB & https://zenonzeni.ca

Summary

Currently a 3rd year honors student in information technology at York University. Careers wise a IT developer that has worked on projects using Java an object-oriented programming language, PHP, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, testing, implementing, and designed web pages, websites, and small applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE & RELATED EXPERIENCE

Information Technology Pass Leader | May 2020 – Present.

York University, Vaughan, Ontario

- Help students with Java programming concepts by analyzing, design, develop and test programs.
- With my partner we would motivate students to answer questions, and as a group solve problems.
- Students who took part of my study sessions do a whole grade letter better in the course.

Ride Operator | March 2018 – November 2019.

Cedar Fair Entertainment, Vaughan, Ontario

- Participated in teams of more than ten and communicate with other associates to operate rides.
- We would follow best practices to meet ride performance goals and safety audits.
- Achieving 2nd best team in the park in terms of performance and safety.

Personal and Academic Projects

Portfolio Website Project (Under Development)

Developed a website portfolio at https://zenonzeni.ca. Running on a Cloud based Linux virtual server.

• Using git and GitHub to push/pull new HTML, CSS, JavaScript updates to keep server up to date.

Designing User Interfaces Web Projects

In this course I guided a team of four to develop prototypes for our bookstore web applications.

- First Project: Designed a low fidelity prototype where users can buy, sell, and exchange books.
 - o We would then perform cognitive walkthrough to test the prototype interface on marvel.
- Second Project: Designed and implement a high-fidelity prototype for our bookstore.
 - We would then perform usability testing to test the high-fidelity prototype interface.

ITEC 2210 System administration

In this course I worked independently to configure and troubleshoot live virtual computer machines.

- First Project: Setup an apache web server and install a web OTRS ticketing system.
 - o I would PowerShell configure the apache web server and setup a MySQL server for the system.
 - o Guest Username: name | Password: password123

Object Oriented Programming JAVA Projects

In this course I independently worked on developing java applications to solve given problems

- First Project: Developed a java app that takes users input for different type of call cards using inheritance.
- Second Project: Developed a java based graphic user interface app that manages a library of books.
- Third Project: Developed an app that counts the numbers in multiple given input text files using threads.

Web Technologies Project

In this course I designed and developed web pages and web applications for specific projects.

• First Project: Designed and developed a product web page with navigation bar and shopping features.

System architecture JAVA Projects

In this course I guided a team of three to update and implement new standard on a smart home app system.

- First Project: Updated a smart home system (java app) to meet architecture standards.
- Second Project: Implement architecture patterns such as adapters, observers into the smart home system.

647-332-1467

Christopher Nguyen

104 Wardlaw Place, Woodbridge, Ontario, L4H0Z9

ZenonZeni@hotmail.com

LinkedIn Profile & GITHUB & https://zenonzeni.ca

UNO Web Application Project

This was an independent high school project where I had to create a web application based on the game UNO.

- Using mainly HTML, JavaScript and some CSS I created a Basic User Interface.
- **UNO Project**: Implemented features like basic AI to play against, drawing cards, placing cards, etc.

SOL Personal Projects & Academic Projects

Created a library database system and wrote SQL queries to create, insert, update, delete.

• **SQL Projects:** I wrote some queries for some tables and inserted, updated, and deleted datasets.

EDUCATION

Honors Bachelor Information Technology | 2018–2022

York University, Vaughan, Ontario

Jimmy K. W. Chan Award

This award will be granted to one or more Faculty of Liberal Arts and Professional Studies students who have completed at least 30 credits at York with a minimum cumulative grade point average of 7.00 (B+).

ITEC Courses Completed/In progress

- Object Based Programming ITEC 1620 (JAVA)
- System Administration ITEC 2210 (Linux and installing web applications on apache)
- Introduction to Analytical Programming ITEC 2600 (MATLAB)
- Object Oriented Programming ITEC 2610 (JAVA)
- Introduction to Data Structures ITEC 2620 (JAVA)
- Systems analysis and design ITEC 3010
- Software Architecture ITEC 3030 (JAVA)
- Designing and Using Interfaces ITEC 3230
- Web Technologies ITEC 3020
- Using and Designing Database Systems ITEC 3220

Scholars Ontario Secondary School Diploma 4 Years Honor Roll | 2014 – 2018

Maple High School, Vaughan, Ontario

Scholars is equivalent to an honor meaning that a student graduated with an average grade of 80% or more.

Relevant Courses Completed

- Grade 12 Computer Science (JAVA)
- Grade 11 Computer Science (HTML, CSS, JAVASCRIPT)

Skills, Knowledge & Tools

Programming, Markup, Script, and Database languages

• Java, Html, CSS, JavaScript, SQL, Bootstrap, and command prompt/PowerShell.

Programming and Server Tools

• NetBeans & eclipse IDE, Git and GitHub, Linux, Apache HTTP, SQL, and Oracle SQL server.

UI/UX & UML Design Tools & Other

• Marvel, Adobe XD, Draw.io, Wix, WordPress, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Windows & Linux.

647-332-1467